Mohammed Albadr

Mohammed is passionate about helping people adapt to changes in any environment, whether it's an organizational change or a system once. As an experienced Change Management Officer, Mohammed has a demonstrated history of working in utilities industry and lately in health insurance sector. Helping in creating and delivering strategies and plans to help ten thousands of employees and entities to maximize the adoption of new programs by honing methods of effective and sustained behavior change.

abla	albadr@hey.com
	(+966) 503 19 4606
Ç	Riyadh, Saudi Arabia
ii	Linkedin.com/in/malbadr

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Change Management Officer

Council of Health Insurance

10/2021-Present

Description

- Performing and supervision change management activities for nphies platform.
 Including impact analyses, interventions identification, training development,
 change monitoring, and lessons learnt consolidation to enhance engagement of stakeholders.
- Developing training and communication materials related to change management activities for nphies.
- Apply change management approach and methodology to identify potential risks, anticipate points of resistance and develop specific plans to mitigate or address concerns.
- Coordinating with Enablement team to align on change needs, communications, and knowledge to enhance stakeholder engagement.

Change Management Analyst

Saudi Electricity Company - Headquarters

02/2012-09/2021

Description

- Supervising two quality programs: Innovation Program and Employee
 Excellence Program. Monitoring the participation of employees and managers
 with the quality programs, including Continuous Improvement Program.
- Organizing quality events, like: Quality Forum (1 time per two years), Quality Days (4 days per year).
- Planning and executing Business Excellence projects Based on EFQM Model in multiple industries, such as: IT, Government, Customer Services, Industrial Security, and HR Development.
- Planning and executing change management and communication projects of various HR initiatives such as: Standardization of Performance Measurements, Manpower Rightsizing in HR and National Grid, Yammer Adoption in SEC, Employee Engagement Surveys, Continuous Performance Management Adoption in SEC, and SEC's Organizational Change Management Methodology.

Member of Executive Youth Council

Saudi Electricity Company - Headquarters

02/2018-01/2019

Description

- · Nominated by SVP to represent HR business line in the council.
- · Led "SEC Investment in Blockchain Technology" initiative.
- Active member of several teams: "R&DI Work Frame", "Customers Services", "Corporate Social Responsibility", "Learning Organization", and "e.YC 2.0".

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree of Computer and Information Sciences, field of: Information Systems

King Saud University

2006-2011

Diploma in Quality Management

Riyadh Chamber of Commerce and Industry

2014-2015

Accelerated Leadership Development Program (ALDP)

The RBL Group

2019-2020

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES



CERTIFICATIONS

Change Management Practitioner

Prosci

04/2021

Internal Assessor

EFQM Model

12/2020

Innovation Leader

AIPMM

10/2019

Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

Integral Solutions

05/2016

INTERESTS



Psychology



Economics



Housing Sustainability



Podcasts



PR & Communications



Translation